Sriram Sandepudi

8879628008 sriram.sandepudi@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/sriram-sandepudi-24515aa

Profile

12+ years experience in General Management, Sales, Channel Management, Influencer Management, Business Development, Demand Planning, Warehouse Space Management, Input Management, New Category Development & Customer Development. Proven track record to deliver business growth across geographies, leading an engaged workforce across the most competitive market landscape.

Experience

ASSOCIATE GENERAL MANAGER, ASIAN PAINTS LIMITED: EAST, KOLKATA – JAN 2020 - PRESENT

Andhra Pradesh, Telangana, Jharkhand, Bihar, Odisha, West Bengal, North East. Revenue of **7000+ Cr** with highest growths in Value and Volume. Handling **10,000+** Direct Dealers, **150+** Distributors with a team of Regional/Area/Commercial/B2B/ Services Managers/500+ Front line Sales and Admin staff with 200+ offroll staff. Decorative Paints, Adhesives, Waterproofing, Implements - track record of delivering consistent market share gains and highest value and volume growths. Leading and Driving focus projects across Division and Regions to create breakthrough.

REGIONAL MANAGER, ASIAN PAINTS LIMITED: AP & TG, HYDERABAD - MAY 2015 - DEC 2019

<u>Andhra Pradesh & Telangana</u>. Revenue of **2000+ Cr** - Largest region. 2 years consistently the fastest growing region. Handling **3500+** direct dealers, **50+** Distributors, 150+ staff with 15+ Managers. Exponential growths in New Categories - Waterproofing, Implements. Successfully launched and executed a Retailer Retention Program for mid rung dealers - prone to shift to competition. Estimated Market Share Gain of 0.75% - Focus on Competition Hot Spots.

SR. AREA MANAGER, ASIAN PAINTS LIMITED: SECUNDERABAD, VIJAYAWADA, VIZAG - 2010 - 2015

<u>Secunderabad</u> - Revenue of **250+ Cr,** Biggest Unit for the region, 11 Team Members. <u>Vijayawada</u> - Revenue **175+ Cr**, 500+ retailers, 7 Team Members, Design and Execution of the Dealer Engagement program for the region, overachieved targets. <u>Vizag</u> - Revenue **100+ Cr**, 300+ retailers, 5 Team Members, 5% MS gain in Vizag local, Collection of Old Dues 20 lacs, CEI improvement of 4%.

SR. BRAND MANAGER, ASIAN PAINTS LIMITED: EXTERIORS, MUMBAI – 2013 - 2014

Handling the largest portfolio by volume, <u>New Product Development</u> - Stone Coatings, Glass Coatings, PrimerCumSealer, Powder Products. <u>Product Improvement</u> - Formulation Changes, Testing and Validation - Lab and Market. <u>Consumer Activation</u> Program in Dehradun on consumer education in Right Painting System, Activations in Key Markets in Northern States, Handling Investigation and Resolution of Customer Complaints.

ASSISTANT SYSTEMS ENGINEER, TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES: BANGALORE- 2005 - 2007

Module lead on the MR-SSP Team - Design of the Customer Service Portal for AMEX.

Skills

<u>Channel Management</u>: Direct Dealers, Distributors, Monthly/ Quarterly/ Yearly Target Achievement, Shop Share Gains, New Category Contribution increase, Sustainability & Profitability, ROI Management, Inventory Management, Business Generation on Digital Platform

<u>Network Spread</u>: Strategic Network Expansion in Gap towns/Geographies/Clusters, Innovative Methods for increasing reach and Market Share Gains, Increasing the Retailing Footprint - New Age Retailing Formats

<u>Input Management</u>: Management of Primary and Secondary schemes within the targets given for spends - to drive sales (Input) and for promotions (BAP)

<u>Demand Planning</u>: Management & Forecast of N and N+1 Demand at multiple depot - SKU combinations to ensure 90%+ OCT and OFR Levels

<u>Marketing Activations</u>: Driving BTL Activations across geographies to ensure achievement of set metrics and delivery of product volume targets - across all stakeholders - retailers, influencers, consumers

<u>Product Strategy</u>: Devising and Implementing of Product Strategy in geographies - New Product Introduction (Benchmarking against competition), Variant Introduction in the same category, Pricing Dynamics, Establishing of High Growth Categories - WaterProofing, Implements & Adhesives

Education

| | PGDM (Marketing) | S P Jain Institute of Management & Research, Mumbai | 2009 |
|--|------------------|-----------------------------------------------------|------|
| | BE (Mechanical) | National Institute of Technology, Karnataka | 2005 |
| | Std 12 (CBSE) | Campion School, Bhopal | 2000 |
| | Std 10 (CBSE) | Campion School, Bhopal | 1998 |